<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: life | YY Every Day]]></title>
  <link href="http://arekyao.github.io/tags/life/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://arekyao.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-10-10T13:59:39+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://arekyao.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Arek.Yao]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Life in China]]></title>
    <link href="http://arekyao.github.io/blog/2013/03/24/life-in-china/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-24T15:54:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://arekyao.github.io/blog/2013/03/24/life-in-china</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="life-is-a-stuggle">Life is a stuggle</h3>

<p>Human being is a magical kind of animal.</p>

<p>And as part of animal family, it has one same feature, facing death, every second and every day.</p>

<p>As you know, Everyone has its limited life.</p>

<p>In the limited life, the experience may be colorful and wonderful. 
Or maybe the opposite with bad luck.</p>

<p>So there is a proverb said, life is struggle.
espcially, in China.</p>

<h3 id="when-boy">When boy</h3>

<!-- more -->

<p>When I am a little boy, I always had lots of complain about my parents.
The topics, which makes me unhappy, are lifestyle and the dealing skill…</p>

<p>Every time conplain happened, Dad told me,</p>

<blockquote class="information">
  <p>When you are old enough, having your children, then you can understand us more.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>At the moment, I did not understand it really.</p>

<h3 id="now">Now</h3>

<p>After ten years, more or less, a child come to my life.</p>

<p>More than half a year passed, suddenly, I got it.</p>

<p>What parents spend on their child, is priceless.</p>

<p>Time and Money, is too much, which is uncountable.</p>

<h3 id="what-we-faced-are-facing-and-will">What we faced, are facing and will</h3>

<p>When we are bobies, we are dangerous because of bad milk.</p>

<p>When we are children and young, we have to study hard to learn something. It’s hard.</p>

<p>When we are grown, work is necessary, which is hard, too.</p>

<p>When we are old, we have to do sth for our children,( like our parents, now )</p>

<p>When we are older, death is welcoming us…</p>

<h3 id="why">Why</h3>

<p>We are dying every day.</p>

<p>The resource in the world is limited…</p>

<p>It’s impossble for humans to share that equally</p>

<p>So we have to struggle for that…and So ….</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Air cleaner and English study]]></title>
    <link href="http://arekyao.github.io/blog/2013/03/10/air-cleaner-and-english-study/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-10T00:28:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://arekyao.github.io/blog/2013/03/10/air-cleaner-and-english-study</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here are two interesting stories.</p>

<p>As you know, Peking is a great city, well-known,as big building, huge population, especially the PM2.5 .
So we decided to buy an air-cleaner.
After considering the brand, the work model of air-cleaning, our choice is the SHARP.
Amazon is my fav E-Commerce platform, we bought gift cards on taobao, then ordered the type.</p>

<p>When the machine is sent home by the Express delivery man, we decided to use it immediately.
Everything is fine, until a month goes away.</p>

<!-- more -->

<p>Yep, you know, the air cleaner should be cleaned every month.
(Some part can not cleaned and it’s disposible)
When I open the machine, I am shocked.</p>

<p>The three layer of the air-filter is wrapped by the plastics.
All of them!!!
Unbelievable!!!</p>

<p>That means we just open it for one month, just the status is open. 
It does not work effectively.
Maybe that’s the reason that the water goes very slowly.
(the air-cleaner have a function: air-humidifying)</p>

<p>The another story is about English study.</p>

<p>Every night, when my baby don’t wanna go to sleep, I will turn on the radio, choose the CNN channel.
Then both She and I will have a good night very soon.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Days We fight against Eczema]]></title>
    <link href="http://arekyao.github.io/blog/2013/02/10/the-days-we-fight-against-eczema/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-10T12:14:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://arekyao.github.io/blog/2013/02/10/the-days-we-fight-against-eczema</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>2012, special year, a cute girl comes into our life, named QianShu.</p>

<h2 id="new-life">New Life</h2>

<p>In her 1st month :</p>

<p>Weight, good.</p>

<p>Height, good.</p>

<p>Breast milk, good.</p>

<p>Everything goes well.</p>

<h2 id="nd-month">2nd Month</h2>

<!-- more -->

<p>However, something changed in 2nd month, that is <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eczema">ECZEMA</a></p>

<p>In the beginning, we did not pay too much attention to it, 
because almost every new born baby would have this reaction and situation.
(ps: difficult to call it illness).</p>

<p>The eczema is not serious, at that time.
Only a few in face, none in body. Looks bearable for me.</p>

<p>We bought YuMeiJing, which is tranditional, old brand in Beijing.
It’s used by lots of workmates, when they were babies.</p>

<p>It works, when in 1 or 2 weeks. 
After that, it turn worse.</p>

<h2 id="rd-month">3rd Month</h2>

<p>The red spots spread from face to the whole body, including legs, back and butt…
From then on, we got that ,we should take it serious.</p>

<p>We got a lot of infomation on Internet.</p>

<blockquote class="information">
  <p>Symptoms:
      redness, skin edema, itching and dryness, crusting, flaking, blistering, cracking, oozing, or bleeding.</p>

  <pre><code>  Scratching open a healing lesion may result in scarring and may enlarge the rash.
</code></pre>

  <p>Cause:
       The cause of eczema is unknown but is presumed to be a combination of genetic and environmental factors.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>At last, We get used to this kind of view;</p>

<pre><code>The Eczema is a reaction, from the body can not get used to Environment.
</code></pre>

<p>Baby is a new life, from Mom’s body.</p>

<p>Everything is new for it.</p>

<pre><code>It needs to get with Environment, like food, air, water...etc.
</code></pre>

<p>So we take some actions to avoid its allergy.</p>

<pre><code>The most dangerous FOOD (which contain much protein):
milk, eggs, fish, peanut, etc.
</code></pre>

<p>After we forbid those food, it did not look better, at first.</p>

<p>Think…for half a day, we found a suspious food, “Mixed Food Oil”.
The mixed oil contain peanut oil…..:(</p>

<p>After that acts, it goes right way.
Baby’s eczema is beaten and lost its battle field.
Though a few wrong things happened, but the general situation is better than before.</p>

<h2 id="th-month">4th Month</h2>
<p>Air Cleaner&amp; Wet machine is bought before Lunar New Year.
So far, hard to say whether it is useful ,
It need time to prove.</p>

<h2 id="now">Now</h2>
<p>Only its face is still red and hot, and there are lots of red spots on face.
Sometimes good, Sometime bad…</p>

<p>The battle is still on….
Maybe it will never ends…</p>

<p>We will fight against it …. </p>

<h2 id="reference">Reference:</h2>

<p>1, <a href="http://blog.sina.com.cn/doctorcui">Doctor CuiYutao</a></p>

<p>2, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eczema">Eczema</a></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
