<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: BabyLife | YY Every Day]]></title>
  <link href="http://arekyao.github.com/blog/categories/babylife/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://arekyao.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-02-10T16:05:23+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://arekyao.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Arek.Yao]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Days We fight with Eczema]]></title>
    <link href="http://arekyao.github.com/blog/2013/02/10/the-days-we-fight-with-eczema/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-10T12:14:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://arekyao.github.com/blog/2013/02/10/the-days-we-fight-with-eczema</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>2012, special year, a cute girl comes into our life, named QianShu</p>

<h2 id="new-life">New Life</h2>

<p>In her 1st month :</p>

<p>Weight, good</p>

<p>Height, good</p>

<p>Breast milk, good</p>

<p>Everything goes well.</p>

<h2 id="nd-month">2nd Month</h2>

<p>However, something changed in 2nd month, that is <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eczema">ECZEMA</a></p>

<p>In the beginning, we did not pay too much attention to it, 
because almost every new born baby would have this reaction and situation.
(ps: difficult to call it illness)</p>

<p>The eczema is not serious, at that time.
Only a few in face, none in body. Looks bearable for me.</p>

<p>We bought YuMeiJing, which is tranditional, old brand in Beijing.
It’s used by lots of workmates, when they were babies.</p>

<p>It works, when in 1 or 2 weeks. 
After that, it turn worse.</p>

<h2 id="rd-month">3rd Month</h2>

<p>The red spots spread from face to the whole body, including legs, back and butt…
From then on, we got that ,we should take it serious.</p>

<p>We got a lot of infomation on Internet.</p>

<blockquote class="information">
  <p>Symptoms:
      redness, skin edema, itching and dryness, crusting, flaking, blistering, cracking, oozing, or bleeding</p>

  <pre><code>  Scratching open a healing lesion may result in scarring and may enlarge the rash.
</code></pre>

  <p>Cause:
       The cause of eczema is unknown but is presumed to be a combination of genetic and environmental factors</p>
</blockquote>

<p>At last, We get used to this kind of view;</p>

<pre><code>The Eczema is a reaction, from the body can not get used to Environment.
</code></pre>

<p>Baby is a new life, from Mom’s body.</p>

<p>Everything is new for it.</p>

<pre><code>It needs to get with Environment, like food, air, water...etc
</code></pre>

<p>So we take some actions to avoid its allergy.</p>

<pre><code>The most dangerous FOOD (which contain much protein):
milk, eggs, fish, peanut, etc.
</code></pre>

<p>After we forbid those food, it did not look better, at first.</p>

<p>Think…for half a day, we found a suspious food, “Mixed Food Oil”
The mixed oil contain peanut oil…..:(</p>

<p>After that acts, it goes right way.
Baby’s eczema is beaten and lost its battle field.
Though a few wrong things happened, but the general situation is better than before</p>

<h2 id="th-month">4th Month</h2>
<p>Air Cleaner&amp; Wet machine is bought before Lunar New Year 
So far, hard to say whether it is useful 
It need time to prove.</p>

<h2 id="now">Now</h2>
<p>Only its face is still red and hot, and there are lots of red spots on face.
Sometimes good, Sometime bad…</p>

<p>The battle is still on….
Maybe it will never ends…</p>

<p>We will fight it …. </p>

<h2 id="reference">Reference:</h2>

<p>1, <a href="http://blog.sina.com.cn/doctorcui">Doctor CuiYutao</a></p>

<p>2, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eczema">Eczema</a></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
